{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Who edited the book 'The Stanley Kubrick Archives'?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Michael Minden",
            "answerChoiceB": "Giorgio Bertellini",
            "answerChoiceC": "Alison Castle",
            "answerChoiceD": "Peter Biskind",
            "answerChoiceE": "Bernard Herrmann",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 170,
            "pageNumberEnd": 170
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was the book 'Film Music: A History' by James Wierzbicki published?",
            "answerChoiceA": "2000",
            "answerChoiceB": "1997",
            "answerChoiceC": "2009",
            "answerChoiceD": "2010",
            "answerChoiceE": "2008",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 170,
            "pageNumberEnd": 170
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the author of 'To Infinity and Beyond!: The Story of Pixar Animation Studios'?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Karen Paik",
            "answerChoiceB": "Enno Patalas",
            "answerChoiceC": "Daniel Keys Moran",
            "answerChoiceD": "Steve Weintraub",
            "answerChoiceE": "Philip Hayward",
            "correctAnswer": 0,
            "pageNumberStart": 170,
            "pageNumberEnd": 170
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following films is associated with the book 'Replications: A Robotic History of the Science Fiction Film'?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Metropolis",
            "answerChoiceB": "Star Wars",
            "answerChoiceC": "Forbidden Planet",
            "answerChoiceD": "WALL•E",
            "answerChoiceE": "2001: A Space Odyssey",
            "correctAnswer": 4,
            "pageNumberStart": 171,
            "pageNumberEnd": 171
        },
        {
            "question": "Which publication included a discussion on 'The Messy Misunderstood Glory of David Lynch’s Dune'?",
            "answerChoiceA": "The New Yorker",
            "answerChoiceB": "The Atlantic",
            "answerChoiceC": "Variety",
            "answerChoiceD": "The Guardian",
            "answerChoiceE": "Entertainment Weekly",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 167,
            "pageNumberEnd": 167
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the subtitle of the book 'The Stanley Kubrick Archives' edited by Alison Castle?",
            "answerChoiceA": "The Complete Works",
            "answerChoiceB": "A Film Odyssey",
            "answerChoiceC": "Cinematic Genius",
            "answerChoiceD": "Behind the Scenes",
            "answerChoiceE": "The Art of Filmmaking",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 170,
            "pageNumberEnd": 170
        },
        {
            "question": "Which year did the book 'Knowing the Score: Notes on Film Music' by Irwin Bazelon get published?",
            "answerChoiceA": "1975",
            "answerChoiceB": "1982",
            "answerChoiceC": "1969",
            "answerChoiceD": "1988",
            "answerChoiceE": "1991",
            "correctAnswer": 0,
            "pageNumberStart": 148,
            "pageNumberEnd": 148
        },
        {
            "question": "Who conducted the interview titled 'An Interview With John Williams' featured in the liner notes for the 'Close Encounters of the Third Kind: The Collector’s Edition Soundtrack'?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Laurent Bouzereau",
            "answerChoiceB": "Michael Kogge",
            "answerChoiceC": "Adam Bray",
            "answerChoiceD": "Kerrie Dougherty",
            "answerChoiceE": "Charlie Brigden",
            "correctAnswer": 0,
            "pageNumberStart": 148,
            "pageNumberEnd": 148
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was the book 'A History of Film Music' by Mervyn Cooke published?",
            "answerChoiceA": "2005",
            "answerChoiceB": "2008",
            "answerChoiceC": "2010",
            "answerChoiceD": "2012",
            "answerChoiceE": "2014",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 170,
            "pageNumberEnd": 170
        },
        {
            "question": "Which book contains a discussion on 'The Second Coming of Sound' by Charles Schreger?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Film Music: A History",
            "answerChoiceB": "Understanding Movies",
            "answerChoiceC": "The Stanley Kubrick Archives",
            "answerChoiceD": "Off the Planet: Music, Sound and Science Fiction Cinema",
            "answerChoiceE": "Film Music: An Introduction in 11 Takes",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 170,
            "pageNumberEnd": 170
        },
        {
            "question": "Which film used spooky synthesized sounds during its opening credits to generate a sense of anxiety?",
            "answerChoiceA": "The Day the Earth Stood Still",
            "answerChoiceB": "Forbidden Planet",
            "answerChoiceC": "E.T.: The Extra-Terrestrial",
            "answerChoiceD": "Close Encounters of the Third Kind",
            "answerChoiceE": "2001: A Space Odyssey",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 127,
            "pageNumberEnd": 127
        },
        {
            "question": "In the movie 'Mars Attacks!', what bizarre event occurs near Lockjaw Kentucky?",
            "answerChoiceA": "A herd of flaming cattle stampedes down the road",
            "answerChoiceB": "A spaceship lands in a cornfield",
            "answerChoiceC": "The town's population disappears mysteriously",
            "answerChoiceD": "Aliens start a dance-off with the locals",
            "answerChoiceE": "A meteor shower lights up the sky",
            "correctAnswer": 0,
            "pageNumberStart": 139,
            "pageNumberEnd": 139
        },
        {
            "question": "In 'Mars Attacks!', what is the initial response of President James Dale to the alien approach?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Order an immediate attack on the aliens",
            "answerChoiceB": "Propose a peace treaty with the aliens",
            "answerChoiceC": "Debate whether to keep the alien approach a secret",
            "answerChoiceD": "Evacuate the major cities",
            "answerChoiceE": "Broadcast a welcome message to the aliens",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 139,
            "pageNumberEnd": 139
        },
        {
            "question": "What happens when the Martians first communicate saying 'We come in peace' in 'Mars Attacks!'?",
            "answerChoiceA": "They start a peaceful dialogue with humans",
            "answerChoiceB": "They immediately torch a dove with a raygun",
            "answerChoiceC": "They gift advanced technology to humans",
            "answerChoiceD": "They disappear in a flash of light",
            "answerChoiceE": "They plant a tree as a symbol of peace",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 140,
            "pageNumberEnd": 140
        },
        {
            "question": "In 'Mars Attacks!', how do the Martians respond when President Dale broadcasts that humans mean no harm?",
            "answerChoiceA": "They agree to a peace treaty",
            "answerChoiceB": "They laugh hysterically",
            "answerChoiceC": "They leave Earth peacefully",
            "answerChoiceD": "They offer technological gifts",
            "answerChoiceE": "They start communicating in English",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 140,
            "pageNumberEnd": 140
        },
        {
            "question": "What action saves humanity from the Martian invasion in 'Mars Attacks!'?",
            "answerChoiceA": "A powerful laser weapon",
            "answerChoiceB": "Negotiations led by the President",
            "answerChoiceC": "The yodeling of Slim Whitman's music",
            "answerChoiceD": "A computer virus",
            "answerChoiceE": "An alien defector",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 140,
            "pageNumberEnd": 140
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term used for the seventh scale degree which resolves upward to the tonic in Western music?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Dominant",
            "answerChoiceB": "Mediant",
            "answerChoiceC": "Leading Tone",
            "answerChoiceD": "Subdominant",
            "answerChoiceE": "Tonic",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 11,
            "pageNumberEnd": 11
        },
        {
            "question": "In a major scale, what is the sequence of intervals?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Whole step, Whole step, Half step, Whole step",
            "answerChoiceB": "Whole step, Half step, Whole step, Whole step",
            "answerChoiceC": "Half step, Whole step, Whole step, Whole step",
            "answerChoiceD": "Whole step, Whole step, Half step, Whole step, Whole step, Whole step, Half step",
            "answerChoiceE": "Half step, Whole step, Half step, Whole step, Whole step, Half step, Whole step",
            "correctAnswer": 3,
            "pageNumberStart": 11,
            "pageNumberEnd": 11
        },
        {
            "question": "In the A major scale, which note is raised a whole step from its natural state?",
            "answerChoiceA": "G",
            "answerChoiceB": "F#",
            "answerChoiceC": "E",
            "answerChoiceD": "D",
            "answerChoiceE": "B",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 12,
            "pageNumberEnd": 12
        },
        {
            "question": "In a natural minor scale, where are the half steps located?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Between scale degrees 2 and 3, and 5 and 6",
            "answerChoiceB": "Between scale degrees 1 and 2, and 4 and 5",
            "answerChoiceC": "Between scale degrees 3 and 4, and 7 and 8",
            "answerChoiceD": "Between scale degrees 2 and 3, and 7 and 8",
            "answerChoiceE": "Between scale degrees 1 and 2, and 6 and 7",
            "correctAnswer": 0,
            "pageNumberStart": 13,
            "pageNumberEnd": 13
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of musical texture consists of a single unaccompanied melodic line performed in unison by multiple instruments or voices?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Homophony",
            "answerChoiceB": "Polyphony",
            "answerChoiceC": "Monophony",
            "answerChoiceD": "Heterophony",
            "answerChoiceE": "Symphony",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 34,
            "pageNumberEnd": 34
        },
        {
            "question": "In homophonic texture, what accompanies the melody?",
            "answerChoiceA": "A rhythmic accompaniment",
            "answerChoiceB": "An independent melody",
            "answerChoiceC": "A harmonic accompaniment",
            "answerChoiceD": "A contrasting rhythm",
            "answerChoiceE": "A repeated ostinato",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 34,
            "pageNumberEnd": 34
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the characteristic of polyphonic texture?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Single melody with accompaniment",
            "answerChoiceB": "Multiple melodies played in unison",
            "answerChoiceC": "Multiple independent melodies",
            "answerChoiceD": "Repeated rhythmic patterns",
            "answerChoiceE": "Melodies played in staggered intervals",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 34,
            "pageNumberEnd": 34
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term for a gradual increase in dynamics in music?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Crescendo",
            "answerChoiceB": "Decrescendo",
            "answerChoiceC": "Piano",
            "answerChoiceD": "Forte",
            "answerChoiceE": "Diminuendo",
            "correctAnswer": 0,
            "pageNumberStart": 36,
            "pageNumberEnd": 36
        },
        {
            "question": "What does 'staccato' indicate in terms of musical articulation?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Smooth and connected play",
            "answerChoiceB": "Shortened duration of a note",
            "answerChoiceC": "Gradual increase in volume",
            "answerChoiceD": "Loud and sudden sound",
            "answerChoiceE": "Continuous and overlapping notes",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 36,
            "pageNumberEnd": 36
        },
        {
            "question": "In music, what is a 'motive'?",
            "answerChoiceA": "A large section of a musical piece",
            "answerChoiceB": "The smallest identifiable recurring musical idea",
            "answerChoiceC": "A repetitive rhythmic pattern",
            "answerChoiceD": "A variation of the main theme",
            "answerChoiceE": "A contrasting section in a composition",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 34,
            "pageNumberEnd": 34
        },
        {
            "question": "In music, what distinguishes an antecedent phrase from a consequent phrase?",
            "answerChoiceA": "An antecedent phrase ends conclusively, whereas a consequent phrase ends inconclusively",
            "answerChoiceB": "An antecedent phrase is always longer than a consequent phrase",
            "answerChoiceC": "A consequent phrase starts with similar material but ends more restfully than an antecedent phrase",
            "answerChoiceD": "A consequent phrase is rhythmic, while an antecedent phrase is melodic",
            "answerChoiceE": "An antecedent phrase contains the main theme, while a consequent phrase contains variations",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 36,
            "pageNumberEnd": 36
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of cadence uses the progression V-I?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Half cadence",
            "answerChoiceB": "Plagal cadence",
            "answerChoiceC": "Authentic cadence",
            "answerChoiceD": "Interrupted cadence",
            "answerChoiceE": "Deceptive cadence",
            "correctAnswer": 2,
            "pageNumberStart": 36,
            "pageNumberEnd": 36
        },
        {
            "question": "What distinguishes diatonic music from chromatic music?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Diatonic music uses multiple scales, while chromatic music uses a single scale",
            "answerChoiceB": "Diatonic music uses pitches from only one scale, while chromatic music adds accidentals to change keys or add pitches",
            "answerChoiceC": "Chromatic music is faster in tempo compared to diatonic music",
            "answerChoiceD": "Diatonic music is primarily instrumental, whereas chromatic music includes vocals",
            "answerChoiceE": "Chromatic music uses only natural notes, while diatonic music includes sharps and flats",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 42,
            "pageNumberEnd": 42
        },
        {
            "question": "How did early filmmakers typically acquire music for their films?",
            "answerChoiceA": "By composing their own original scores",
            "answerChoiceB": "By using pre-existing music from other entertainment forms like vaudeville and theater",
            "answerChoiceC": "By hiring famous composers to create new music",
            "answerChoiceD": "By using popular radio music of the time",
            "answerChoiceE": "By conducting public competitions for new music",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 43,
            "pageNumberEnd": 43
        },
        {
            "question": "What role did vaudeville theaters play in the evolution of film music?",
            "answerChoiceA": "They introduced the concept of live orchestral accompaniment for films",
            "answerChoiceB": "Vaudeville theaters were the first to use recorded soundtracks for films",
            "answerChoiceC": "They provided a venue for testing new film technologies",
            "answerChoiceD": "Resident musicians in vaudeville theaters played along with films, using their existing music collections",
            "answerChoiceE": "Vaudeville performers composed original scores for early films",
            "correctAnswer": 3,
            "pageNumberStart": 44,
            "pageNumberEnd": 44
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of music accompanied Max Skladanowsky's early film screenings in Berlin?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Original scores composed specifically for his films",
            "answerChoiceB": "Silent screenings with no musical accompaniment",
            "answerChoiceC": "Improvised music by a solo pianist",
            "answerChoiceD": "Popular dance pieces like polkas, marches, and waltzes",
            "answerChoiceE": "Recordings of famous classical compositions",
            "correctAnswer": 3,
            "pageNumberStart": 44,
            "pageNumberEnd": 44
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the guide mention as a significant feature of pulp magazines?",
            "answerChoiceA": "Their educational content",
            "answerChoiceB": "Use of low-quality paper stock",
            "answerChoiceC": "Focus on highbrow literature",
            "answerChoiceD": "Promotion of classical music",
            "answerChoiceE": "Exclusively non-fiction articles",
            "correctAnswer": 1,
            "pageNumberStart": 166,
            "pageNumberEnd": 166
        }
    ]
}
